[BLANK AUDIO].
[空白录音]。123
We are going to start learning to execute code with the most basic statements in
让我们开始学习如何使用C语言中 最基础的语句来执行一段代码
C and build up to more complex statements from there.
然后在此之上构建更复杂的语句
Here we have two variable declarations, one for
在这里我们有两个变量声明
int called x followed by one for int called y.
一个整数变量x 和另一个整数变量y
If we execute first statement, we will create a box labeled x.
如果我们执行第一句语句 我们会创建一个标记为x的方框
The variable x is uninitialized, so
变量x尚未被初始化 所以
we will place a question mark in the box for its value.
让我们在方框里写一个? 来暂时代表它的值
If we execute the second statement,
如果我们执行第二条语句
we will create another box labeled y which is also uninitialized.
我们会创建另一个标记为y的方框 它也没有被初始化
Uninitialized variables are bad,
没有被初始化的变量很不好
as they lead to bugs in your code which may be hard to find and fix.
因为他们会导致你的代码中 出现难以排查和修复的bug
Now let's look at another example which initializes the variables.
现在来看另一个例子 它不仅声明且初始化变量
Here, the first statement declares an int called x.
这里的第一句语句声明了一个变量x
Executing it behaves exactly as before.
执行它的结果和之前的例子中一模一样
We have made a box for x, which has an unknown value in it.
我们给变量x创建了一个方框 并且方框中包含一个未知的值
However, the next line of code assigns 4 to x.
但在下一句代码中 我们把4赋值给x
Executing this line puts a 4 in the box for x.
执行这行代码会把数值4放在方框x里
Now x is initialized and we know that it has the value 4.
现在x已经被初始化了 我们知道它值为4
The next line shows the declaration and
下一行代码则在同一语句中
initialization combined in a single statement.
同时包含了声明和赋值
Executing it both creates a box for y and puts the value 6 in that box.
执行它将会给y创建一个方框 并把数值6放在方框里
Of course, variables are only useful if you make use of the values that they have.
当然 除非你用到这些变量被赋予的值 否则它们毫无用处
Here, the code first declares x and initializes it to a 4.
这里的代码声明变量x并初始化它的值为4
Let us execute that statement.
让我们来执行这句语句
Next, it declares y and initializes it to x + 2.
接下来的语句声明y 并且把它的值初始化为x+2
To perform this statement, we must evaluate the expression on the right-hand
为了执行这句语句 我们需要计算等号右边的表达式
side of the equal sign, x is 4, so x + 2 is 6.
x的值为4 所以x+2的值为6
We create a box for y and put a 6 in it.
我们给y创建一个方框并且把数值6放进去
The last statement creates a variable z and initializes it to y- x.
这里的最后一行语句创建一个变量z 并把它初始化为y-x
As you might expect, you would take the value of y, which is 6 and
你可能已经猜到了 这行代码用y的值6
the value of x which is 4 and subtract them to get 2.
并减去x的值4 得到结果是2
You would then create a box for z and initialize it to 2.
接下来 给z创建一个方框 并且初始化它的值为2
Great, now you know how to execute code with variable declarations and
很好 现在你已经知道怎么执行变量声明
assignment statements.
和变量赋值的语句了